I am from Ukraine, the city of Khmelnitsky, where are you from?
Я из Украины город Хмельницкий Вы откуда
And you and I are Russia, as I understand it, you are the
А мы с тобой Россия я так понимаю вы
USSR,
СССР
I was not born that I was born in the USSR in 81.
не я родился что я родился в СССР 81
What year were the boys born in
году Вы какого года рождения мальцы
2005, can you tell me what was
2005 можете мне вот рассказать что
good in the USSR, here I am just a
хорошего было в СССР вот я просто
person who was born 10 years old  lived in the
человек который родился 10 лет прожил в
USSR Tell me the boys what
СССР Расскажите мне мальцы в чем прикол
was the fun in the USSR it’s
был в СССР
good Now you have a paid education
хорошо Сейчас у тебя платное образование
Yes, look I’m wondering, I just
Да смотри Мне вот интересно я просто
heard this fairy tale about the leading economy
слышал эту сказку про ведущую экономику
for some reason, for example, you had to stand in line for bread,
почему-то например за хлебом нужно было
butter, they gave two packs in your hands, they only
масло давали две пачки в руки только
sold the queue
продавали очередь
or nothing that
или ничего что
the pigs were fed with bread, I may not come
свиней хлебом кормили я может не приду
who was fed for yours, I tell you
кого кормили для твой я рассказываю я
personally I stood in line for bread I personally
лично Стоял в очереди за хлебом Я лично
stood in line for butter with my mother
Стоял в очереди за маслом с мамой потому
because they gave if mother stands alone and give
что давали если мама стоит одна и дают
two packs up to mass 17,
две пачки до масса 17
you understand if she has  there are a lot of tanks,
понимаете если у неё очень много танков
I understand correctly that in your opinion there is
я правильно понимаю что по вашему там
this third voice that is
вот этот третий голос который где-то
broadcasting somewhere from behind the screen, he says that the USSR
из-за экрана вещает он говорит что СССР
could make tanks but could not make
мог делать танки но не мог сделать для
bread and butter for its citizens
своих граждан хлеб и масла
for whom this country was not
для кого эта страна была получается не
for the people,
для народа
yes
да
confirm that this country was not in the
подтверждаете что эта страна была не в
interests of the people,
интересах народа
why then did these two of your friends
а зачем тогда вот эти твои два друга
hang the flag of a totalitarian country
повешали флаг тоталитарной страны
says Because look, it was an
говорит Потому что смотри это было
economic crisis here is an
экономического кризиса
economic say tell me in the
вот экономический скажи скажи в
Soviet Union when people lived
Советском Союзе когда люди жили
normally What year
нормально В каком году
was [ __ ] In short, there was nothing
[__] было Короче ничего не было
look  photos of the
посмотри фотографии
eighty-first year of birth from 81
восемьдесят первого года рождения с 81
to the beginning of 90
до начала 90
for bread 5 years old at 6 years old at seven years old
за хлебом 5 лет в 6 лет в семь лет
eight years old
восемь лет
and before that well tell me
а до этого хорошо вот этого скажи мне В
what year there was no economic
каком году не было экономического
crisis in the USSR there
кризиса в СССР
was stagnation
был застой
And when was when was the
А когда был когда был
Soviet Union was there  72 years there
Советский Союз был там 72 года там
conditionally Yes there or there 70 something,
условно Да там или там 70 чем-то вот
almost 70 years did not last When it was
почти 70 лет не дотянул Когда в нем было
good to live in it for at least some year Tell me 45
жить хорошо хоть какой-то год Скажите 45
when there was not a damn thing 45 85
когда там был ни хрена не было 45 85
Look, I now take a shorter one For example,
Смотри я сейчас короче беру Например
a photo of the
фото
USSR store
СССР
look empty on the counter,
посмотри пусто на прилавка
it is understandable that
это понятно
already at the end of the 19th century they were
были уже в конце 19 века
not portable, which
не переносные которые мог позволить
every person could afford appeared when the
каждый человек появились когда
Soviet Union collapsed and
развалился Советский Союз и пришли
Western technologies came here Well then
западные технологии сюда Хорошо тогда
Whose photographs of
Чьи фотографии
those photographers that everyone did not have
тех фотографов которые у каждого не было
a camera Under the Soviet Union were not
фотоаппарата При Советском Союзе не было
Good
Хорошо
i wait not everyone had a camera the one
я жду не у каждого был фотоаппарат тот
who was a professional photographer
кто был профессиональный фотограф Да у
yes he had a camera here mine
него был фотоаппарат вот у моего
he is an american
он американец
you said affordable because look
ты сказал доступный потому что смотри
cameras appeared
фотоаппараты Я сказал
in the nineteenth century
в конце 19 века и уже были фотоаппарат
century
это камеры фотографии есть конца 19 века
Look, here you can look, I just
Смотри вот ты можешь посмотреть просто я
don’t understand. Well, I understand some kind of
не понимаю Вот ладно я понимаю какие-то
grandfather, you know which is nostalgia for
там дед знаешь который вот ностальгия по
his youth. Well, you’re a small pulley, you
его молодости Ну ты ж мелкий шкив ты
didn’t even live in this USSR.
вообще даже не жил в этом СССР Что тебя
then
адекватный тот кого нет в кадре потом
the more adequate one that is closer to the
более адекватный тот который ближе к
camera, he is silent and the most inadequate is
камере он молчит и самый неадекватный то
that closer to the flag,
что ближе к флагу
I see, I see Yes, and so I blew up
вот вижу вижу Да вот и так я подорвался
you have nothing to say by arguments, you
у тебя нечего сказать по аргументами ты
start a rag a rag and who are you
начинаешь тряпка тряпка а вы на кого
studying for boys
учитесь пацаны
Geography Department of the Moscow
географический факультет Московского
State University And this is who  you will
Государственного А это кем будете
work as geography teachers
работать учителями географии
No, you
Нет
can say, look, for example,
можете сказать смотрите например
surveyors in the USSR how well
геодезисты в СССР насколько хорошо
they earned
зарабатывали
no
нет
how affordable cars were in the USSR
насколько доступны были машины в СССР
In what year was
В каком году
it not
нет
in the USSR
в СССР
that when Ukraine appeared
что когда Украина появилась
modern Ukraine, even like the
современная Украина то даже как и
modern Russian Federation in
современная Российская Федерация в 1991
1991 after the collapse of the USSR,
году после развала СССР
they say that
утверждают что
10  centuries Well, look, the fact is that the
10 века Ну смотри Дело в том что
territory of our territory so had
территория нашей территории так были
different state formations,
разные государственные образования
for example, Russia, so here we are, in fact, We are
например Русь так вот мы фактически Мы
the same population, so The heirs of those
тоже самое население так Наследники тех
people who lived in Russia, you are a
людей которые жили на Руси вы вот
search city
поискового города
That is, you are from a territory where there were no
То есть вы с территории где не было
Slavic tribes, for example, let's
славянских племён правда
take  Italy and Ancient
например возьмем Италию и Древний
modern Italians are related to
современный итальянцы имеют отношение к
ancient Rome Why,
древнему Риму Почему
because
потому что
at the moment it is very difficult
на данный момент это очень тяжело
to say because it is very good,
сказать потому что это очень хорошо а
but you, living in Tyumen, are related,
вот вы живя в Тюмени имеете отношение к
for example, to
например
those states that were on your
тем государством которые были На вашей
territory there 500 years ago,
территории там 500 лет назад
your state is so Russian
ваше государство так Российская
Federation but quite young She
Федерация но достаточно молодой Она
appeared in 91 he is how
появилась 91 году ему сколько это
old he is
получается
32 years old yes In two years your
32 года это да Через два года вашему
state yes, that is, you have a little
государству да то есть у вас маленькая
history like a state Why
история типа государства Почему
[music]
[музыка]
in Kiev the beginning was
в Киеве начало было
Novgorod there was no Russia there was
Новгороде не было никакой Руси было
a capital in Kiev
столица в Киеве
Slavic tribes here  Russia Yes, there were
славянские племена вот Русь Да там были
Slavic tribes Drevlyans glade there,
славянские племена древляне поляне там
street northerners Yes,
уличи северяне Да вот у вас на
some
территории Москвы жили какие-то
Slavic tribes lived in Moscow during Russia
славянские племена во время Руси
Who lived there
Кто там жили
Drevlyans
древляне
look The fact is that look before it
смотри Дело в том что смотри раньше не
was not so you know the name of the whole people
было так знаешь название народа целого
so there were tribes for example Slavic
так были племена например славянские
tribes on the territory of Russia got here a clearing
племена на территории Руси добыли вот
Drevlyans northerners there you turn your
поляне древляне северяне там ты вертит
horns there you had a little bit of evidence
рожки было там уличии чуть-чуть было
in your territories so on the
у вас на ваших территориях так вот на
territory of modern Russia some
территории современной России какие-то
Slavic tribes lived during Russia
славянские племена жили во время Руси
or not
или нет
Which
Какие
I’m going
Я иду
Look I say that this  topic Look, I’m here
Смотри я говорю что эту тему Смотри я
in the ninth in the ninth century there was the
вот в девятом в девятом веке было
state of Rus, this is the state Yes, of the
государство Русь это государство Да того
same people that now lives in Ukraine, that
же народа что сейчас живет в Украине то
is, we Ukrainians, it turns out it
есть нас украинцев получается она
was called Rus then,
называлась тогда Русь
these Slavic tribes lived there, these are
там жили вот эти славянские племена это
our ancestors in your territory of Moscow
наши предки у вас на территории Москвы
on the territory of Klyazma there  There were
на территории там Клязьма там Тюмени
no Slavic tribes there during Russia.
никаких славянских племён во время Руси
Tell me when What kind of migration
Вот расскажи мне когда Какое переселение
happened
получилось
when historians do not know any
когда историки не знают никакого никакой
such migration of the Slavs? On the contrary, they
миграции славян такой Туда наоборот на
migrated
юг мигрировали
their point of view to the south. And how do I live here?
свою точку зрения А как я тогда тут
in Russia,
православные люди это все кто в России
Orthodox, these are Russians, then
православные это русские потом уже
nations like Ukraine began to be developed,
начали вырабатываться нации как Украина
this is the Western part
это вот Западная часть
Look, I’ll see this, what’s your name, what’s
Смотри я вот этому как тебя зовут то что
in glasses, so that
в очках чтобы по имени обучался
Andrei Ukrainian could study with me by name Yes, look, you’re
у меня Андрей украинский Да смотри вы
just like that, when there was Russia We
просто такой вот э когда была Русь У нас
had Slavic people here  tribes the
тут жили славянские племена у вас жили
Finno-Ugric tribes of
финно-угорские племена
Erzya lived in you, and so on, look Then
эрзя и так далее да вот смотри Потом
then Yes, that
потом Да что
Finno-Ugric tribes lived on the territory of the Moscow region of the Ivanovo region of the Vologda region, you
жили финно-угольские племена ты
open the map of the 9th century to the settlement of the
открываешь карту 9 века расселению
settlement of tribes Slavic tribes
расселение племён славянские племена
are localized here Belarus and part of the
локализируется тут Беларусь и часть
Smolensk region still  the
Смоленской области еще локализируется
Slavic tribes are localized there, here the
славянские племена там вот
Finno-Coal tribes are right there is
финно-угольский племена прям вот есть
everything then what happened Yes,
все потом что получилось Да
from Russia
из России
they sent the prince there to you as a
присылали князя туда вам это как
governor For example, if now a
губернатор Вот например если сейчас
governor is sent to Buryatia from Moscow because of
бурятию из Москвы пришлют губернатора
this, the Buryats did not become Russian
из-за этого буряты не стали русскими
true Well, that’s
правда
also from Kiev  before the prince was sent
Ну и вот также из Киева до присылался
to collect tribute and the prince was still there he
князь для сбора Дани и князь еще там у
had hundreds of these soldiers there and the
него там сотни этих воинов было а
population was all Finno-Ugric, but
население все было финно-угорска но
since they didn’t have a written language,
поскольку письменности у них не было да
they adopted such writing from
такой письменность они перенимали из
Kievan Rus and therefore, just like now
Киевской Руси и поэтому также как сейчас
you have it in Russia  Udmurts
вот у вас есть в России удмурты
Finno-Ugric people Yes, but they already
финно-угорский народ Да но они уже язык
forget their language Yes, and it turns out that
свой забывают Да и получается
the majority speaks Russian, also
большинство говорит по-русски вот также
in the ninth-tenth century, before a bunch of these
в девятом десятом веке до куча вот этих
Finno-Ugric tribes Yes, they switched to
финно-угорских племен Да они перешли на
Slavic languages ​​​​so because
Славянский языки так из-за того что
the state imposed Slavic languages
государство навязывало славянские языки
That is, you are
То есть вы
representatives Yes, here are some of these
представители Да вот каких-то этих
Finno-Ugric peoples who adopted the
финно-угорских народов которые приняли
Slavic languages ​​\
славянские языки что ничего страшного в
u200b\u200bthat there
этом нету
is nothing wrong with that
нет
What do
Что
I say that you Yes, in those
я говорю что вы Да вот на тех
territories, Russian
территориях российский никакого
had never had anything to do with Russia
отношения к Руси не имели никогда
in Kiev Yes, and she stopped  its
в Киеве Да и она прекратила свое
existence after the Tatar-Mongolian
существование после татаро-монгольского
Invasion, Russia never moved
Нашествия никогда Русь не переезжала ни
to any Moscow, not to Suzdal, why it
в какую Москву не в Суздаль почему это
turns out Russian, it turns
получается русский
out No, not a Russian
получается Нет не русский
concept Invented at the end of the 19th and beginning of the 20th
понятие Придумано в конце 19 начале 20
century,
века
then they came up with it
придумали потом
a little earlier before that they
чуть раньше
didn’t call it they called
до этого не называли этого называли там
you there you’re great growth came up with the name
вас велика роста придумали название
how the anthem of the Russian Empire sounded then
как тогда звучал гимн Российской империи
about the Russian land, it doesn’t matter at all How it
про русскую землю это вообще пофиг Как
sounded in the Russian Empire appeared in
звучал в Российской империи появилась
1721 until the 18th century
1721 году до 18 веке Руси уже не было
Russia was
Российская империя полтысячили лет
no more  there were Russians once again look at
там не было русских еще раз смотри на
your territories there
ваших территориях
was no one again look I didn’t
не было никого еще раз смотри я не
say nobody is afraid
сказал никого не боится
Kiev after the Mongol-Tatar Invasion
Киев после монголо-татарского Нашествия
so Russia ceased to exist
так Русь прекратила свое существование
so Why the hell do you say that you have
так С какого фига вы говорите что у вас
Russia there this Moscow is related to
там Русь это Москва имеет отношение к
Russia
России
What kind of Russian
Какая русская
What does the word Moscow mean
Что означает слово Москва
Where did this word Moscow come from?
Откуда пошло это слово Москва
Slavic peoples lived
Да ну вот там не славянские народы жили
with you
у вас
in Finalgorsk,
финалгорске
the etymology of the word Yes, there are different types of
этимология слова Да есть разные там типа
linen water there, and so on
полотенная вода и так дальше
from different places in the Moscow
с разных у вас на территории Московской
region, the Finno-Coal people lived, measuring
области жил финно-угольский народ меряя
it already their language has died out. They
он уже ихний язык вымер Они
assimilated completely
ассимилировались полностью
now Russians live there now,
сейчас там русские живут сейчас там
look now they live there  modern
смотри сейчас там живут современные
Russian so-called Yes, this is a figurative
русские так называемые Да это образное
name for completely different peoples
название абсолютно разных народов
who see the sign Sign
которые видишь знак Знамение
Ukraine plunged the Soviet Union of God
Украина повергла Советский Союз Божия
to defend the
на защиту
word of the game not Boys break loose, let's
слова игры не Пацаны срываемся
shorten that kid the third shawn in
давай короче той пацан третий шоны в
the frame you are the most adequate I will
кадре ты самый адекватный Я за
fork out And you spent the day off
разветвлюсь А ты проводимыми выходной